lp.org 2002-12-08

# Libertarian Party: Online Privacy Policy

Are you a Libertarian?  
  
Take the **World's Smallest Political Quiz** and find out!

First time here? Try our new WWW Site Tour and see what we have to offer.

The LP News is the official newspaper of the Libertarian Party.

Plan for Upcoming Events.  

|  | **Privacy Policy**

This web site is owned and administered by The Libertarian Party.

Our postal address is:

> 2600 Virginia Ave. NW, Suite 100  
>  Washington D.C. 20037

We can be reached via e-mail at hq@lp.org or you can reach us by telephone at (202) 333-0008

## General Issues

For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes the visitor's host/domain name, but not his e-mail address. We collect only the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, aggregate information on what pages consumers access or visit, and any other information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey or contact information provided to us in various sign-up forms and interactive elements of the site.

### Details: Unidentified visitors and aggregate information

The information we collect from general, unidentified visitors is used to improve the content of our Web site, to customize certain content and/or layout of our site for visitors who opt for our "regionalization" feature, and it is not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes. The "regionalization" feature uses cookies to customize Web page content based on the user's volunteered information: their U.S. state and/or ZIP code. 

We collect and use aggregate information from all our site's visitors (derived from your internet host, the duration and details of your visit, and the entrance and exit path to/from our site) in order to understand and improve our site's performance, design, architecture or content over time. No other information from general visitors is collected, used or shared in any way not specifically stated above.

### Details: Self-identified visitors and individual information

The information we collect from self-identified visitors to the site, through the process of various interactive elements, forms, surveys or polls, or other such data collection processes on the site is handled in any of a number of ways:

  * We collect contact information volunteered by site visitors for the purpose for which each visitor volunteered it - to receive information, goods, or services, as the case may be.
  * We may choose to share that contact information with other, outside organizations whose philosophies, goals and purpose is complementary to our own and who we think may provide you with further valuable information or services.

If you do not want to receive postal mail from us in the future, please let us know by or sending us e-mail at hq@lp.org and including in your message the text "DEACTIVATE." When writing, please be sure to provide us with pertinent information such as your membership number or current contact information. You will not receive any further postal mail from us, and your name will not be shared with outside organizations.

If you would like us to stop sharing your contact information with other organizations, please let us know, again by writing to hq@lp.org and including in your message the text "NO MAIL." You will continue to receive mailings from us, but your name and contact information will no longer be shared.

You may also write to us with the option "REDUCED MAIL" - You will receive limited mail from us, including LP News (if your membership/subscription is current), membership renewal notices, and our annual report. You will not receive the periodic (monthly or bi-monthly) progress reports.

Rental/exchanges are always for one time use and only involve postal addresses. We do not rent/exchange any of our email lists or phone numbers with outside organizations. We share e-mail addresses and telephone numbers only with our state affiliates.

## Ad Servers

We do not partner with or have special relationships with any ad server companies at this time. We do not employ the use of banner advertising on the site. 

## Other Sites

The Libertarian Party web site contains links to the web sites of other companies and organizations which may employ their own privacy protection policies and publish notices of their own regarding online privacy. We encourage you to seek out and read such privacy protection notices whenever they are available in order to remain informed regarding the use of your personal information. For example, the Libertarian Party web site employs the use of "frames" in linking to a feature entitled the "World's Smallest Political Quiz," an interactive application developed, hosted and owned by The Advocates for Self-Government (). Please be sure to read and understand the privacy policy available at the Advocates' site. 

## Future Changes and Updates

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our Web site to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our Web site periodically.

Upon request we provide site visitors with access to contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number) that we maintain about them.

Users can access this information by writing to us at the postal address provided at the beginning of this document. Users can have this information corrected by including a note to that effect in their requests for information, or by sending separate communications, also to the address listed. Please note that in the specific case of Libertarian Party members and subscribers to our monthly periodical, the LP News, change-of-address forms are available online in the "Services & Sales" and "LP News & Events" portions of our web site, respectively.

## Security

We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site. When we transfer and receive certain types of sensitive information such as financial or transaction information, we redirect visitors to a secure server which encrypts this information before sending it to us. 

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at the above addresses or phone number. 

Thank you,  
HQ Web Staff  
The Libertarian Party

|  |    

**Your State's LP**  
Regionalize content on this site according to your home state.  

**Against Censorship**

**For Privacy**  
  
---|---|---|---|---
